# CRISTIAN ARIZA

FRONT END DEVELOPER

+54 9 11 2388-5841 | mecrisariza@gmail.com | <u>crisariza.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | Buenos Aires, Argentina (UTC -3)

# **EDUCATION**

### Full Stack Developer

HENRY | BUENOS AIRES (REMOTE) | DEC 2020 – FEB 2021

Throughout the online program, fundamental Computer Science topics such as Data Structures and Algorithms were taught.
Achieved during 800 hours of instruction, projects, and hard work.

## **SKILLS**

React

Redux

Next

JavaScript

**REST** 

TypeScript

CSS

HTML

TailwindCSS

Git

**SCRUM** 

Node

**Express** 

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Sequelize

# LANGUAGES

English | Fluent Spanish | Fluent

## **SUMMARY**

Developer with 2 years of experience. Looking forward to creating new complex software engineering projects. Thrilled to use programming skills to help an amazing company create a fantastic product. Excited about business, startups, crypto and cutting-edge tech. Dedicated to creating code quality over quantity.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## FRONT END DEVELOPER

ACCENTURE | BUENOS AIRES (REMOTE) | MAY 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed a platform that managed +150 web applications, providing security solutions with a modern and simple to use experience.
- Saved +20 hours per month by innovating in a new automated content delivery to developers, using a modern framework such as NextJS.
- Created a front-end from scratch using React, Redux and TailwindCSS, providing a phenomenal user experience and interface.
- Improved the API queries speed by 30% through requiring and sending only the needed JSON data, which enhanced the overall app experience.
- Increased satisfaction rate versus the old platform from 80% to 95% by implementing feedback provided from developers, also improving the overall communication.
- Promoted within 12 months for outstanding performance from Junior to Semi-Senior role, acquiring more responsibilities, advanced tasks and making critical thinking.

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

HENRY | BUENOS AIRES (REMOTE) | MARCH 2021 - APRIL 2021

- Led the back-end and front end development of a 5+ person team creating an
  ecommerce website, providing useful features such as secure authentication,
  automated emails to 100% of the user orders, payments an user-friendly paywall
  (Stripe), search the website stock, ability to add products to the cart, and more.
- Increased the back-end response time by 50% through better queries in PostgreSQL with Sequelize, accomplishing a better user experience.
- Decreased loading times by 40% in the front-end using techniques such as lazy-loading, reducing server calls, reducing image sizes, and more.
- Decreased the loading times of the website by 20% through optimizing the React components states using Redux, leading to a more modular code.
- Designed the user interface and experience with modern, simple and beautiful styles.